Don't try to deny it!
June 15th, Stellar Year 2148
You throw us out here on the battlefield
and treat us like weapons,
while you get to watch from your
warm and safe place inside the walls,
and it doesn't bother you at all!
If that's not treating us
like pigs, what is?
You think that if you just act nice
and talk to us every day,
that counts as treating us
as human, don't you?
You've never even asked us
for our real names!
Theo.
Raiden, you don't need
to defend this white pig—
Theo!
Got it.
Handler One, kill the synchronization.
Um—
The battle's over.
You don't need to monitor us.
Laughing Fox went too far,
but none of us are in the mood
for a friendly chat with you.
I'm sorry.
I don't want to die.
I'm sorry, Kaie.
I did the same thing as the white pigs.
And tainted your death.
Go! Go! Go!
June 16th, Stellar Year 2148
You can do it!
Theo!
Get him!
Sorry...
Theo!
Next! Next!
Don't screw it up!
Go!
Whitey!
Stay put! Whitey!
Theo, that's a fox, not a cat.
And it's scary.
And it's not laughing!
You're supposed to be Laughing Fox.
Shut up.
Are you bothered by
what you said to that woman?
No, I'm not!
Well, it bothers me.
Yup.
Theo...
Don't move!
Gotcha! Gotcha!
It bugged me the way this came off.
Also the way he always
has just one button done.
Who cares?
It's just like you, but...
Forget it!
What we saw yesterday
wasn't like you at all.
The way you said it wasn't good,
but it reminded me of the Fox Commander.
Just give it up, guys.
Well, we're all jealous,
because you met someone like that.
What's this about?
Someone who'll always be important to you.
They were never like that for me.
Listen, Shin.
You'd better not break it next time!
Stay put until we get our new parts shipment!
If I can.
Hey, Theo.
Don't do anything stupid like him.
You guys are all such kids!
He looked like he was about
to burst a vein, as always.
I'd like to keep him from getting mad,
once in a while.
That's probably impossible.
Thank you.
What would the commander
have said to that Handler?
The Fox Commander?
Yeah. Would the commander have gotten mad?
Well, it doesn't matter.
That white pig who thinks she's a saint
is probably never going
to use the Para-RAID again.
Your commander wouldn't have said that.
That's what you think, isn't it?
Kirschblüte
Do you need something, Handler One?
June 16th, Stellar Year 2148
It just shows that, in the end,
you're a citizen of the Republic.
We have to accept
that we live in our own world.
That's not okay.
I could never forgive myself if I did that.
So what would be okay, then?
Go to the 86th District
and fight alongside them?
You can't do that.
What you need to do now is spoil yourself.
I made too much pudding.
Annette, I'm sorry, but I'm not the mood.
That's not healthy.
This world is a wonderful place,
where you can sneak in a pudding snack
in the middle of the day.
It's not wonderful.
Not at all.
Why is it such a big deal
that you didn't ask their names?
You don't need to know them.
You're never going to meet them.
Henrietta Penrose.
What?
That's your name.
I know your name. We're friends.
So what?
A name is who you are.
And I didn't even think of that.
I wasn't treating them as human.
You're over-thinking this.
You and the Eighty-Six aren't even friends.
But we're all human!
If you really thought that,
you would've asked their names right away.
This is a great time to stop trying
to get any closer to them.
Why are you so set against them?
Because there's nothing I can do.
There's pudding here. And not there.
We're different from them.
In every way.
So any way we get involved
just leads to us having regrets.
But—
Lena, the war's already started.
There's no going back to how things were.
Just quit being a Handler
and come to the lab!
I said...
I can't quit being a Handler.
You should listen when
your best friend gives you advice,
Vladilena Milizé.
Let's go the battlefield.
And see everything that's happening.
You're at war, right, Father?
That's right.
And we're doing something even worse.
Something worse?
Yes.
We have to bring this to an end.
Quickly.
Can you take us
a little past the frontline base?
Yes sir, Colonel.
What's wrong?
Uncle...
I still can't forget it.
The last place my father took me.
The battlefield in District 86.
I'm sad about what happened to him.
But I'm glad I could see it.
Glad?
Yes.
Because I saw the 86th District
with my own eyes,
I was able to learn the truth
about this country.
I was able to hold the ideals
that the Republic threw away.
So...
Vaclav was a kind man who wanted
to make the Republic a better place.
I'm sure he was a good husband
and a good father.
That's why he decided to teach you
the truth about this country.
As a friend, I think it's a terrible shame
an enemy attack took from us
a man with such a strong sense of justice.
But there's something he didn't realize.
What?
Just like the rest of the Republic,
he wasn't doing any more than watching.
In the end, no matter how much you talk
about equality, it's not you who's fighting.
He felt, subconsciously, that only
the Eighty-Six die on the battlefield.
That's why he was able to take you
to the battlefield.
The fact that he did something so reckless
for the sake of his ideals
proves his ignorance and stupidity.
Lena, I don't want you to be like him.
That's enough.
You're doing a good job.
It's also my responsibility
for giving you a tough unit to deal with.
I wanted you to feel for yourself
the reality of this nation.
But you don't need to do it
if it's too much for you.
No, I'll continue to act
as Spearhead's Handler.
What does the Republic flag stand for?
Freedom, equality, brotherhood,
justice, and nobility...
What are you—
Are you upholding that?
Look at the real world.
Those beautiful things are nowhere
to be found in the Republic.
You are too focused on seeking ideals.
From others, and yourself.
Ideals are ideals precisely
because they are unattainable.
Seeking them when you know
they're impossible is foolish
and cowardly, don't you think?
Here's today's update on the war
from San Magnolia Military HQ!
You throw us out here on the battlefield
and treat us like weapons,
while you get to watch from your
warm and safe place inside the walls,
and it doesn't bother you at all!
If that's not treating us
like pigs, what is?
Damage taken on our side was minimal,
with no human injuries or fatalities!
Do you think we're out here fighting
because we want to?
Combat via highly advanced,
You locked us out here! Forced us to fight!
ethically responsible drones has resulted
in zero fatalities on our side!
You've caused the deaths of millions
over the last nine years!
The day when our nation's
righteousness finally smashes
And you do nothing to stop it.
You think that if you just act nice
and talk to us every day,
the evil remnants of the
wicked Empire is not far off!
that counts as treating us
as human, don't you?
Glory to the Republic of San Magnolia,
and to the five-color flag!
You're not cut out for that job.
You should let someone else take your place.
Not that way! Kirschblüte!
Before you regret it.
I don't want to die.
Para-RAID, activate!
Synchronization target:
Undertaker!
War Casualties Cemetery
Do you need something, Handler One?
Undertaker, can we talk for a moment?
Go ahead.
I'm sorry...
About yesterday. And everything before it.
I'm really sorry.
Um...
I'm Lena. My name is Vladilena Milizé.
I know I should have asked sooner, but...
Would you please tell me your names?
If you're bothered by what
Laughing Fox said to you,
then there's no need to be.
What he said isn't what we all think.
You didn't create this situation,
and you can't fix it on your own.
We know that.
You don't need to blame yourself
for not doing the impossible.
But it was rude not to ask your names.
There was no need to ask.
Why do you think it's required
to use call signs on the Para-RAID,
even though the Legion can't intercept it?
And why are the Processors'
personnel files locked?
So Handlers won't have to think
of Processors as human, right?
Yes.
Most Processors die within a year.
They probably assumed all that death
would be too much for a Handler to bear.
But that's cowardly! I...
And I was, too!
Honestly, I was going to run away.
But I don't want to stay a coward forever.
So please, tell me your names.
Your real names!
Kirschblüte, the girl who died yesterday,
was Kaie Taniya.
Wehrwolf, our XO, is Raiden Shuga.
Laughing Fox is Theoto Rikka.
Snow Witch, Anju Emma.
Gunslinger, Kurena Kukumila.
Black Dog is Daiya Irma...
That's all of them.
Thank you.
Please, call me "Lena."
I've been told your name.
What's your rank?
Major. I was just promoted, though.
I'll call you Major Milizé
from now on, then.
Is that okay?
Yes.
What are you doing?
Leaving Kaie's name behind.
Eighty-Six don't get graves.
So in my first unit, we all made a promise.
When someone died, we'd carve their name
into a fragment of their Juggernaut,
and the survivors would carry it.
So that the last of us to survive
would take the others to their final destination.
I was the last. I've always been the last.
So that's my job in this unit, too.
You've been doing that for five years.
How many people have died?
Five hundred sixty-one.
Including Kaie.
And all of them...
I remember them.
Because I have to take them with me.
All the ones who died
fighting alongside me.
Until I reach my final destination.
And that's why you're "Undertaker."
That's part of it.
I never faced the people I let die.
I just felt bad about it.
I'm sorry. Truly.
Um... If it's possible,
I'd like to apologize to everyone.
Shall I connect you?
R-Right now?
No, I'm fine.
One moment.
All personnel...
I'm sorry about yesterday,
and for the way I've behaved until now.
My name is Vladilena Milizé,
and I'm a Handler.
I wasn't treating you as humans.
And I didn't even realize it.
Of course you would reject me.
But if you would still answer me,
then please tell me your names.
Shin already told you, right?
What a pain.
He did.
But you didn't tell me yourselves.
Why couldn't you keep your mouth shut?
You regretted it, right?
Maybe not what you said,
but how you said it.
The mark on my Juggernaut is a laughing fox.
But I got it from someone else.
From who?
The combat commander
of the first unit I was attached to.
A commander so cheerful and chipper
it was almost stupid.
A former soldier, and stupidly strong.
An Alba, like you.
A weirdo who said it wasn't right
to make the Eighty-Six fight alone,
and came back to the battlefield.
I hated them.
But they never left.
They stayed and died.
They died being the rear guard,
defending other Processors.
I'm not asking you
to do the same thing they did.
But as long as you're inside the walls,
you're not our equal.
And we won't accept you as one of us.
That's all.
That's the good person Kaie
was talking about, huh?
It's not just them.
She was referring to everybody
who fought the hardest they could.
Along with this crappy world
that was made by the same Alba as them.
Okay, I'm done talking.
Oh, I'm Theoto Rikka.
Call me "Theo" or "Rikka" or
"cute little shit-pig," whatever you want.
I'm sorry for the way I acted.
Enough. Get over it already.
XO Raiden Shuga.
Yes.
First, let me apologize.
Your nightly calls made us think of you
as a wannabe saint and hypocrite pig
not realizing how much of a pig she was,
and we laughed at how stupid you were.
I apologize for that. I'm sorry.
And now that I've said that...
As Theo said, we don't think of you
as an equal or a comrade.
You're an idiot who's stomping on our faces
while lecturing us with platitudes.
That won't change no matter what happens.
That's how we'll always see you.
If that's okay with you,
we'll keep talking with you to kill time,
but personally, I don't recommend it.
You're not cut out to be a Handler.
You should quit.
If it will help you pass the time,
I'll keep calling.
You're a moron, too, huh?
Oh, right, send that map.
You were too busy crying yesterday
to send it, right?
I'll send it right away!
Bye, Major Milizé!
This has been Daiya Irma.
Haruto. Nice to meet you.
Anju Emma, Major!
Kurena Kukumila.
I'm Lecca!
Chise.
Kino!
Thank you, everyone.
I'm sorry, Undertaker.
Yes?
I haven't heard your name.
Did you not want to give it?
No, I'd just forgotten.
I'm sorry.
Shinei Nouzen.
"Nouzen"?
Is something wrong?
Do you know someone named "Shourei Nouzen"?
His personal name was Dullahan,
and his mark was a headless knight.
He's my brother.
"I'm With You."